What's it like?
>> Yeah, it's it's humbling, you know, very
appreciative. Uh I think anytime you
your peers view you in a good light, uh
it means a lot to you. So, yeah,
humbling and and grateful for that.
>> I tell you what, Green Bay is full of uh
they got a lot of really good people up
there on that front office. Um I think
when you look at Milt Hendrickson, John
Wjakowski, Richmond Williams, Lee
Gendainer, um all those are very capable
of of sitting in this chair. Uh they all
bring a lot to the table, different
personalities, uh different skill sets,
but uh but all will have an opportunity,
I think, in time to to do this.
>> What does that mean to John Robinson?
>> Yeah, Kyle Smith and John Robinson for
me uh will be tremendous resources. Um,
obviously with J-Rob, he's sat in this
chair before. Um, he will be a
tremendous sounding board for me. He
understands what's ahead, the pitfalls,
the kind of the way that I looked at it
when I was piecing this together is, you
know, obviously the current GM, John
Robinson has been a GM. Kyle will be a
GM. So, I thought all of us together
would be a, you know, a pretty uh,
pretty good team. John, so the whole
team they made the move at quarterback
later,
you know, with you guys coming in, you
guys, what are you doing to evaluate the
quarterback position heading this year?
>> Yeah, so we're evaluating the entire
roster, right? Um, as it as it pertains
to Tua, uh, you know, I know that
question is coming, so I'll just get
ahead of the curve. Um, you know, we've
had conversations with Tua and his rep
representation. Everything's on the
table. Uh including the potential of a
trade. Uh we don't know which way that's
going to go. There's a lot of different
factors at play, a lot of conversations
being had. Um but but evaluating the
roster. You know, Quinn did a nice job
uh towards the end of the year. Um
excited about what's ahead for him. You
know, Tua, I thought even though things
didn't go well at the end of the year,
uh did did some good things along the
way. And uh it's my job to infuse
competition into that room along with
every other room as we go down the road.
>> Go ahead.
>> As you build an identity as a
consider
>> I mean I think you have to be in tune
with what's going on in the in in the
division. Um we have a a way of doing
business. We have kind of a standard
that we want to adhere to pillars within
our process. Um, but yeah, I think you
always have to be aware of of who you're
playing within the division and what
it's going to take to beat those
football teams or compete with those
football teams.
Sure.
I mean, I think at the end of the day,
like when you're talking about the
draft, you you know,
you have to do what you need to do to
help your football team. Um, age, injury
history, um, consistency of performance,
all of that comes into play. I think if
you can help it, you don't want a a
player going into or close to going to
into a second contract around 30 years
old. Having said that, the climate of
college football, uh there are
situations where you're going to have to
look at those things and consider uh
consider that um to to get good football
players.
>> Sure. I mean, I think when you're
talking about tour or any other player,
obviously there's a financial component.
Um there's a level of play component.
We're going to exercise discipline,
uh, long-term vision and future with
every decision we make, whether it's Tua
or any other player within our
organization. Um,
>> speaking of quarterbacks, you had a
pretty good one agent. What do you see
from the guy that you traded for a
couple years ago to the guy?
>> Sure. Uh, very happy for Malik on a
personal level. The situation that he's
put himself in. Malik's a very very good
kid. Um he's it's a testament to him and
and how he played and the opportunities
that he got. Um as it pertains to the
Miami Dolphins, listen um I think I'd be
lying to you. Any team that is
potentially in a quarterback situ where
a needy quarterback situation, uh if
they tell you they're not talking about
Malik Willis, that would be a lie. But
we've talked about a lot of people, a
lot of free agents. Uh Malik's just one
of them. Um, we have no idea what that's
going to look like in our room. Is it
going to be multiple draft picks? Is it
going to be a free agent along with
Quinn? Who knows? We have so many
factors at play. We got a lot of
decisions to make as we move through the
next couple weeks. Um, but I wish Malik
the best. Uh, a lot of a lot of like for
the human being. He's a great kid.
>> What are some of the challenges going to
Say that one more time. I'm sorry.
>> Sure. I think you just have to set um
you have to set a standard and an
expectation as you move through. Like
part of my job, if you get away from the
roster for a second, part of my job as
we move down the road is to be very
clear in the way that I communicate with
our personnel staff going through the
free agency window, the uh the draft
window, make sure they understand their
roles and their responsibilities, and
then sit back and watch them work. Where
are we strong? Where are we weak? what
potential changes do we need? I will say
to this point, I've been very pleased.
Um, I thought they did a wonderful job
in draft mu uh draft meetings. I thought
their background on players was very
thorough. Um, I did not see anybody in
that room who did not have a deep
passion and care for what they were
doing. Uh, which was was good to see.
Yeah, you know what? I don't want to get
into all the whatifs in terms of who we
may acquire, may not acquire. Um, I
understand the question. Um, obviously,
you know, it's no secret that we're in a
bit of a a strain salary capwise. Um, I
think, you know,
you can get cre you can you can always
do what you want to do within the salary
cap. that means you have to kick things
down the road. We're in a position
without speaking specifically. I think
we're in a position where we need to get
back into a healthy
a healthy state within our salary cap.
Um so yeah, I mean I think anytime you
look around the league, there are teams
that kick the can down the road every
week. So can you? Yes. Will we? I'm not
here to say that.
>> Things are definitely different with you
taking over, but the Dolphins haven't
been afraid to release or trade star
players. Is there Russian that you as
you want to build this thing up with.
>> Yeah, I mean um good question. I think
the right way to approach that is there
are players that we see as building
blocks as we move down the road. My job
as the general manager, if the phone if
the phone rings, I have to listen. Um,
any player is tradable at a certain
price, but there are certain guys that
we definitely want to be part of the
long-term future uh that are on this
roster currently that we think are the
right kind of guys. Um, they're wired
the right way. They infuse the locker
room with the right kind of uh grit,
toughness, leadership that you're
looking for and and they're good players
on the field.
about who?
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. I mean, Howie goes without saying.
He's one of the best in the business.
Very creative in how he does things. Uh
very forward thinker. Um I mean, his
success and the success of that team
speaks for itself. A ton of respect for
Howie.
>> Seems like an ideal way.
with a young quarterback.
Why do you think nobody's been able to
>> Yeah, I mean
I think you can't look at those things
in a vacuum. There's so many factors at
play. Um I don't want to speak on what's
going on in other people's buildings. I
don't I'm not in that building. I'm not
uh I don't know what's happening with
the roster. I don't know in particular
what issues they're having injury-wise
off field. I can't really speak to that.
>> Is that what you aspire to do?
>> Yeah, I think anytime you have a young
quarterback, you want to build
infrastructure. You want to put a good
football team around them so you can go
be as competitive as possible.
>> Sure. I mean, look, I grew up in Green
Bay. you know the history there. Um, you
know, I was not with Ron Wolf, but Ron
Wolf's fingerprints were all over what
we did as we as I moved through my
career with Ted Thompson and uh and
Brian Gudens. I mean, if you I think
back when we had in 200, you know, we
had Aaron was our starter in 2008, but
he was a young quarterback. You know, he
was not Aaron Rogers yet. And we drafted
uh Brian Braum in the second round and
Matt Flynn in the seventh. And I think
if you just look at the history of what
Ron did, who Brett Favre's backups were
with Hasselback and Aaron Brooks and Ty
Demer and you can go on and on. Uh Kurt
Warner, I don't think you can ever have
too many quarterbacks. I think that the
the the value of the position um cannot
be overstated. So I think that you have
to infuse as much competition into that
room every year uh that you that you
possibly can. But I think it depends on
where you are as a team as to when you
do that valuewise within the draft.
Well, I mean, you only have 53, right?
So, I mean, if you have if you have a
bunch of guys that are taking up roster
spots that, you know, aren't going to
play, I just don't think you have the
flexibility to do that. Um,
Do you have a response?
>> Sure. Uh, could not have been more
impressed with Kelvin or Patrick. They
did a phenomenal job. They were
legitimate candidates. The truth of the
matter is there's there's a pace and a
timing as to which you have to move to
make sure that you're going to get your
guy. You can't get left holding the bag.
Um at that point of the at that point in
the process, it was clear to us that
Halfley was who we wanted to go after
and he had other options on the table.
So, so there was a timing element to
where we had to we had to get on down
the road to make sure that we weren't
going to lose him to somebody else.
Cannot say enough good things about
Patrick Graham. I was with him in Green
Bay. He's a phenomenal coach. He will
continue to do great things in this
league. And Kelvin was very, very
impressive and I have no no doubt that
he'll have a he'll be a head coach in
this in this league one day.
>> His energy, um, his command of the room,
uh, I think if you if you want to build
a bully, you know, Kelvin, he can lead,
he can lead men. There was a toughness
and a command that he had and his
ability to articulate that. Um, and it
wasn't false bravado. I mean, he walked
out of the room and we all kind of
looked at each other like, "Wow, that
was really impressive." I have no doubt
as he gets down the road in his career,
he'll have a lot of opportunities.
>> John, the identity of the whole Dolphins
spread out quickens,
right? You guys
are going to bring the table
as far as
>> Yeah, I mean, so as it pertains to me,
I'm looking for good football players.
My job is to build a foundation. Um,
something that's long-term, sustainable
in terms of scheme. I mean, that's a
that's a Bobby Slowick, Jeff Hafley,
Sean Dugen question. I'll let those guys
speak to the particulars there. You
know, it's my job, our job as a
personnel staff to bring in as many good
football players as we can so that they
have the flexibility to call the game
aggressively. That gives them
flexibility to call the game. Those kind
of things.
Sure.
I mean, I think the first thing I would
say when it comes to Tyreek Hill in
particular, um, marvelous player, right,
one of one uh, Hall of Fame caliber,
very, very appreciative of what he
accomplished here in Miami. I think when
you look at um, just where we were as a
salary cap, obviously he's dealing with
an injury right now, his age, it just
made sense for us to move on down the
road. Um, he was very understanding. he
he he could not have been more
professional in our phone call. Um and
then with Chub, you know, kind of along
the same lines, very good player,
accomplished a lot of really good
things. Uh there's just salary cap
implications where we kind of need to
get not kind of, we need to get younger
and cheaper and and those were some
avenues for us to do that. But, uh very
good players here, very appreciative of
what they did while while they were with
the Dolphins.
Yeah, I think you have to take it all
into the equation. I mean, I'm I'm not
here to say that it should or it
shouldn't. That's that's a team by team,
case by case basis in terms of how you
how you weigh that, you know. Um, you
know, I think like like I said, I I
think a lot of Malik is is a human
being. Um, he's a talented player. Uh,
what his future holds, I'm not I'm not
here to say. Uh whether that pertains to
the Miami Dolphins or somebody else, we
got we got a lot of work to do here to
figure that out.
>> I think Tua had some bright moments. I
think Tua, if he was standing here
today, would tell you there was some
moments he wishes he had back, some
decisions he had back. Um Tua
accomplished a lot of or has
accomplished a lot of really good things
in his time in Miami. I think people
that are Miami Dolphins fans should be
proud to have had him here and we'll see
where it goes. You know, I think Tua
believes that he can still be a um a
high level quarterback in this league.
Um I think that's what his desire is to
do. You know, where that happens remains
to be seen whether that's here or
elsewhere.
in a similar situation.
>> Sure. Again, I mean, I I'll put it on
me. I think I think where we are as a
roster, like like here's here's the
reality of it, and you guys know this.
We have eight picks, right? I mean, as
we sit here today, we have eight picks.
It's my job to be very creative and
aggressive in how we use our eight picks
and then our draft our undrafted free
agency process and then the 53 cut and
then you know practice squad steals. We
got to build this thing out but we have
to build it out so that it's sustainable
over time. You can't do that overnight.
Uh, so at the end end of the day, I
mean, to answer your question, I'm going
to do everything in my power 365 days a
year to infuse competition into every
room by the avenues given within player
acquisition.
>> Sure. I mean, I think anytime you're
evaluating offensive linemen, it first
and foremost it comes back to the tape,
right? I mean, are they productive
football players on film? Um, and then
this is part of the process. How they
measure, how they run, how they jump.
But, you know, you're dotting eyes and
you're cross and tease, but but this
process is just one part of the process
for me, and I'm speaking for me, um,
obviously you want big guys that are
good athletes, but at the end of the
day, it comes back to how do they play
football? Um, and so yeah, I'm I'm
looking for good football players. I'm
not looking for guys that are are
particularly good testers, but don't
show up on tape.
>> I think getting to know the kids. I
mean, obviously, look, all of it's
important. I mean, all of it's
important. If it if it wasn't, we
wouldn't be here. I think when you get a
chance to watch these guys interact
with, I I say teammates, the guys that
they're at the combine with, when you
get to see how they compete in the
drills, obviously the metrics, you know,
how they test athletically. Um, and then
when you get to sit in a room and
interview them and see how they
articulate themselves and get a feel for
them, um, ask them what's important to
them, what do they want to accomplish
when this is all said and done, the
things that they say back to you. It
allows you to uh to get a look under the
hood. What do they prioritize? Is it
winning? Is it things that are uh
more me and I? Or is it about the team?
Those are the things that as we build
this out in Miami, we want culture guys.
We want we want guys that prioritize uh
winning football games over individual
success, if that makes sense. So, so
those are the things that I'm looking